Finding Aid for Services for Students with Disabilities (University of Michigan) publications, 1974-ongoing
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Services for Students with Disabilities (University of Michigan) publications. 1974-[ongoing], 1974-1994
University of Michigan. Services for Students with Disabilities.
0.4 linear feet
03110 Bimu 2
Includes annual reports, flyers, maps, pamphlets and reports. Also includes the manuals Disability Resource Guide for the University of Michigan; Meeting the Challenge: A Guide to Barrier Free Learning; Resource Handbook for Students with Handicaps at the University of Michigan; and The University of Michigan Learning Disabilities Handbook for Students, Faculty and Administration. Contains the newsletters The Advocate; Breakthrough News; The Disabled Student Services News; and SSD Gazette.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The publications are received periodically from the unit (donor no. 8123 ).
The publications are open for research.
For background of this unit, please consult the history found in the finding aid for Services for Students with Disabilities (University of Michigan) records.
The Services for Students with Disabilities Publications are divided into two series: Unit Publications and Student Publications. The bulk of the publications document the programs and activities of the Services for Students with Disabilities office.
The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the Services for Students with Disabilities. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Services for Students with Disabilities.; University of Michigan. Disabled Student Services Program.; University of Michigan. Office of Disabled Student Services.; College students with disabilities--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Singer, Emily K.--University of Michigan Learning disabilities handbook for students, faculty and administration, 1991.; University of Michigan. Disabled Student Services Program.; University of Michigan. Office of Disabled Student Services.; Disability resource guide for the University of Michigan.; Meeting the challenge guide to barrier free learning.; Resource handbook for students with handicaps at the University of Michigan.; Advocate.; Breakthrough news.; Disabled student services news.; SSD gazette.
Genre Terms:
Annual reports.; Flyers.; Manuals.; Maps.; Newsletters.; Reports.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series includes annual reports, brochures, flyers, manuals, maps, newsletters, and reports. The annual reports from the period 1973 to 1983/84 are very similar to those found in the President's Report (Call Number Fimu; B3a), but there may be some differences. The 1993/1994 annual report is not published anywhere else. There are also three maps, dated 1981, 1987 and 1993, describing campus accessibility for handicapped students, faculty, and staff included in this series. There is also a 1988 report from the Transportation Task Force Committee which investigated how to bring the university into compliance with the Civil Rights Act of 1973 to provide safe and reliable transportation to those with physical challenges.
  The bulk of the publications are manuals and newsletters. The manuals include faculty and student handbooks published in 1993. The purpose of the Faculty Handbook is to provide an introduction to the various disabilities that affect students at the university and to suggest adjustments in teaching style or classroom environment that the faculty can make to facilitate students' learning at the university. The Student Handbook was written to familiarize potential students with the services available to disabled students at the University of Michigan. The Resource Handbook for Students with Handicaps includes university policy and procedures regarding equal opportunity for handicapped students, information about accessibility, educational resources, financial aid, and health services, as well as support services and advocacy programs. The University of Michigan Learning Disabilities Handbook for Students, Faculty, and Administration is a guide for faculty, staff and students to help them meet the special needs of students with learning disabilities including time management tips and stress relief.
  The Bentley Historical Library has issues of the newsletter Disabled Students Services News from 1977, 1978 and 1988. The library holds issues of The Advocate from 1979 to 1982, though volume 2 is missing. It appears that volume 2 was, very likely, never published. The Breakthrough News was published in 1983. The Resource was printed in 1984. There is one issue of News Notes released in 1988. There are several issues of the SSD Gazette dating from 1989 to 1994 and the S.S.D Flash which was issued in 1990. All of these newsletters include information on tutoring, transportation, support groups, and special services offered by the office of Services for Students with Disabilities and the University of Michigan.
  - Annual Reports
    - 1974-1983/1984 (Box 1)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - 1976-1993 undated (Box 1)
  - Flyers undated (Box 1)
  - Manuals
    - Barrier Free Design: A Design Manual Based on the Michigan Construction Code by Georges Selim, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Disability Resource Guide for the University of Michigan
      - 1993 (Box 1)
      - 1995 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Handbook, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Meeting the Challenge: A Guide to Barrier Free Learning
      - 1978 (Box 1)
      - 1981 (Box 1)
    - The Resource Handbook for Students with Handicaps at the University of Michigan, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Student Handbook, 1993 (Box 1)
    - The University of Michigan Learning Disabilities Handbook for Students, Faculty, and Administration by Emily K. Singer, [ca. 1991] (Box 1)
  - Maps
    - Accessibility, 1981, 1987, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - The Advocate
      - 1979-1980 undated (Box 1)
      - 1980-1982, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Breakthrough News, 1983, undated (Box 1)
    - The Disabled Student Services News
      - 1977 (Box 1)
      - 1978 (Box 1)
      - 1988 (Box 1)
    - News Notes, 1988 (Box 1)
    - The Resource, 1984 (Box 1)
    - SSD Gazette, 1989-1994 (Box 1)
    - S.S.D. News Flash, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Reports
    - Report of the Transportation Task Force Committee, 1988 (Box 1)
- Student Publications
  The Student Publications series contains publications published by student groups within the Services for Students with Disabilities. The Learning Disability Society created several undated brochures, calendars, and flyers to describe their activities on campus.
  - The Learning Disability Society
    - Brochures undated (Box 1)